demon.net 2019-06-18

# Read the Vodafone privacy and cookies policies

Our privacy and cookies policy gets updated from time to time. Whenever we make a change, we’ll post this on our website and let you know if there is a material change.

We have revised our privacy and cookies policy, refreshing it to tie in with the launch of our new Privacy Portal.  

  **Last updated: 29  August 2018**

**How to use this privacy and cookies policy**

In this policy, we explain how we collect, use, share and protect your personal information when you use our products and services and our website.

**Who we are**

We are Vodafone Limited.

In this privacy policy:

  * “we/us” means Vodafone Limited
  * “third party” means someone who is not you or us
  * “Vodafone Group” means Vodafone Group Plc and any company or other organisation in which Vodafone Group Plc owns more than 15% of the share capital

Our registered office is Vodafone House, The Connection Newbury, Berkshire RG14 2FN. We are registered in England under company number 1471587 and registered with the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), registration number Z1933885.

**How to contact us**

Your opinion matters to us – if you have any questions about our privacy policy or your privacy settings, please [submit your query](http://www.vodafone.co.uk/gdpr-privacy-query-form/index.htm) and a member of our dedicated team will respond to you. If you would like to mail us by post directly, send it marked the “Privacy Team” to Vodafone House, The Connection, Newbury, Berkshire, RG14 2FN.

**Our principles**

Vodafone is committed to respecting your privacy. We take privacy, security and complying with data protection and privacy laws seriously.

Here are Vodafone’s core [Privacy Commitments](https://www.vodafone.com/content/index/about/privacy.html). We aim to put these commitments at the heart of everything we do.

The information we collect about you and how we collect it can vary depending on the products and services that you use and subscribe to, how you have used the products and services, and how you have interacted with Vodafone even if you aren’t a customer, or what we have obtained from a third party with permission to share it with us.

To find the privacy supplements for all our products and services, please go to the 'Privacy and our products and services' section of this Privacy Portal.

Vodafone will process your personal data based on:

  * **The performance of your contract or to enter into the contract** and to take action on your requests. For example, so you can make calls and texts, and browse the internet on your phone, we process things like the numbers you dial, how much data you’re using and when you’re doing it so we can provide connectivity. This also enables us to generate your bill, based on your usage. We also need to conduct credit checks when you apply for a product or service.
  * **Vodafone’s legitimate business interests** , for example, fraud prevention, maintaining the security of our network and services, direct marketing, and the improvement of our services. Whenever we rely on this lawful basis to process your data, we assess our business interests to make sure they do not override your rights. Additionally, in some cases you have the right to object to this processing. For more information, visit the 'Your rights' section of this policy.
  * **Compliance with a mandatory legal obligation** , including for example accounting and tax requirements, which are subject to strict internal policies (such as retention periods), procedures, and your right to restrict usage of your data, which control the scope of legal assistance to be provided.
  * **Consent you provide** where Vodafone does not rely on another legal basis. Consent may be withdrawn at any time. When you give your consent, you will be given details on how to change your mind or visit the 'Your rights' section of this policy for more information.

We will collect your personal information when you, for example:

  * Buy or use any of our products and services
  * Use our network or other Vodafone products and services
  * Register for a specific product or service
  * Subscribe to newsletters, alerts or other services from us
  * Contact us through various channels, or ask for information about a product or service
  * Take part in a competition, prize draw or survey
  * Visit or browse our website or other Vodafone Group websites
  * Have given permission to other companies to share information about you
  * Where your information is publically available
  * Are the customer of a business that we acquire

We also collect information from certain organisations, where appropriate and to the extent we have legal grounds to do so. These include fraud-prevention agencies, business directories, credit check reference/vetting agencies, billing calculating agencies and connected network providers.

When you visit our premises, we may also collect information about you on CCTV as part of our security and crime prevention measures.

We use cookies (small text files stored in your browser) and other techniques such as web beacons (small, clear picture files used to follow your movements on our website). For more details on this and how to opt out of these, please see the 'Cookies' section of this policy.

The types of information we may have are, where applicable:

  * Your name, address, phone and/or mobile number, your date of birth, gender and email address.
  * Your credit or debit card information, information about your bank account and other banking information. For example, you’ll have to give us this information when you open an account with us. We’ll collect the data necessary to process a payment whenever you make a purchase.
  * Your traffic data. This is data we see as part of providing you with connectivity, like the numbers you call, the time and duration of the call or how you are using data.
  * Your location data. This can be precise where it uses Global Positioning System (GPS) data or by identifying nearby mobile phone masts and Wi-Fi hotspots and you enable location-based services or features. Or less precise where, for example, a location is derived from your IP address or data such as a post code or name of a town or city.
  * Your contact with us, such as a note or recording of a call you make to one of our contact centres, a Live Chat, an email or letter sent, or other records of any contact with us.
  * Your account information, such as dates of payment owed or received, subscriptions you use, account numbers or other information related to your account or included in My Vodafone.
  * Credential information – we’ll collect passwords, hints and similar security information used for authentication and access to accounts and services.
  * Your preferences for particular products, services and lifestyle activities when you tell us what they are, or we assume what they are, based on how you use the products and services.
  * See the 'Cookies' section for details on what we collect using cookies, web beacons and other technologies, including ad data.
  * Your browsing history. We don’t have a history of the sites you browse, as this is limited for a short period of time to enable the connection to be made. If you have given permission, Vodafone may collect the categories of website you have browsed on your mobile, device or PC, for example sports, music or news and use these interests to send you personalised marketing or show you personalised advertising. You can opt out of advertising through Cookies. In the case of marketing, see 'Opting out of marketing' in the 'Your rights' section of this policy.
  * Information we obtain from other sources, such as credit agencies, fraud-prevention agencies, and from other data providers. This includes demographic data, interest-based data, and internet browsing behaviour.

We’ll also get information about how you use our products and services, such as:

  * The level of service that you receive – for example, network or service faults and other events that may affect our network services or other services;
  * Details of your use of the specific services or products, for example: every time you use your mobile phone, a record is kept. This includes the number you called or sent a text or picture message to, the length, date and time of that call, text or picture message and your approximate location at the time that the communication takes place (based on the location of the nearest cell that you sent that call or message from). The same is also recorded every time you receive an incoming call or message. We don’t, however, keep a record of the content of your calls or messages.

We will use your personal information for the following purposes:

**_1\. To provide you with your service_**

**Processing your order and providing you with your products and services**

  * To process the products and services you’ve bought from us, and keep you updated with the progress of your order.
  * To provide the relevant product or service to you. This includes other services not included in your agreement with us (PayPal, for example), services that use information about where you are, and to contact with you messages about changes to the products or services.

**Billing and customer care**

  * To bill you for using our products and services, or to take the appropriate amount of credit from you.
  * Contact you if the billing information you provided us with is about to expire or we’re not able to take payment.
  * To respond to any questions or concerns you may have about our network, products or services.

**Service messages**

  * We will contact you with customer service messages to keep you updated with current information about products and services you’ve taken. For example, changes to our terms and conditions or service interruptions.

**Providing roaming services**

  * To improve your roaming experiences, to ensure that we’re meeting our commitments around fair use, to detect and resolve fraudulent use of our networks (and our partners' roaming networks) and to solve technical issues if you are experiencing any.
  * To understand how Vodafone is performing in providing roaming services, whether roaming services and related products are working as intended, or whether improvements are needed to make roaming better.

Vodafone uses personal data such as your name, email address, password, mobile phone number and call records in order to do this. Vodafone creates aggregated and statistical management reports from this information that do not identify you individually. Vodafone may also take this personal data and anonymise it so that more in-depth analysis of our roaming services can be undertaken. This helps Vodafone to develop its roaming services for customers without identifying users in an individual way.

**_2\. To improve our service_**

**Improving and innovating our products and services**

  * We collect anonymous, de-identified or aggregate information in order to improve the service we offer to everyone. None of these analytics are linked back to you in any way.

**Managing our networks and understanding network usage**

  * To protect our networks and manage the volumes of calls, texts and other uses of our networks. For example, we identify peak periods of use so we can try and ensure the networks can handle the volume at those times.
  * To understand how you use our networks, products and services. That way we can seek to review and improve these, and develop more interesting and relevant products and services, as well as personalising our products and services.

**_3\. Marketing and  tailoring our service to you_**

**Marketing**

  * As our customer, we will contact you to keep you informed about new and existing products and services, competitions, prize draws and other promotions. We may also send you newsletters or white papers and occasionally invite you to participate in market research. We tailor these messages based on the products and services you’ve bought from us in the past, or information we have from third parties such as Experian.

  * With your permission, we can use your calling and messaging activities, location information and browsing information to further tailor our messages to you. To **opt in** text **Start Network**  and/or **Start Location**  to **9774** on your Vodafone mobile. Alternatively, you can contact a member of our [customer services](http://www.vodafone.co.uk/contact-us/) team, or use our [privacy query form](https://www.vodafone.co.uk/gdpr-privacy-query-form/index.htm) to have a member of our dedicated team respond to you.

  * If you have given your permission, we will also contact you to let you know about products and services of Vodafone Group companies and those of other companies which we think may interest you

  * There are various ways that we may do this – including by email, post, phone, text, picture message or notifications through our apps.
  * You can control your marketing permissions and the data we use to tailor these communications at any time. See 'Opting out of marketing' within the 'Your rights' ** ** section of this privacy policy.

**Advertising online**

  * To deliver advertising that is relevant to you, you’ll also see targeted advertising online based on the use of cookies. This is known as interest-based advertising. It can be on websites belonging to the Vodafone Group, those of other organisations as well as other online media channels such as social media sites. We may also combine data collected via the cookies with other data we have collected. If you don't want any information processed through the use of cookies, check the 'Cookies' section in this Privacy Portal. It explains how to control and opt out of cookies.
  * Remember that opting out of interest-based advertising doesn't stop advertisements from being displayed – it's just that they won’t be tailored to your interests.
  * You will also see advertising in your social media, for example in your Facebook or Twitter feed. If you don’t want to receive this advertising, go to the relevant platform’s ad settings.

**_4\. Research and analytics_**

We use a variety of analytics methods including what is commonly referred to as “Big data analytics”. Big data analytics are mathematically driven analysis techniques on large and varied data sets (that is why it is “big” data) to uncover hidden patterns and hitherto unrevealed trends. At Vodafone we take governance of big data analytics seriously. Our data scientists are required to sign up to a Code of Ethics. We have a strict use case process that requires that privacy and data protection law checks are carried out before any use case commences. We also have strict rules ensuring that personal information is anonymised or de-identified at the appropriate stage in the process.

We use our analytics to, for example:

  * Conduct market research and to carry out research and statistical analysis, including to monitor how customers use our networks, products and services;
  * Frame our marketing campaigns and determine how we might personalise those;
  * Provide reports to third parties (such reports don’t contain information which may identify you as an individual). For example, as part of [Vodafone Analytics](https://www.vodafone.co.uk/about-this-site/our-privacy-policy/vodafone-analytics/index.htm)

**_5\. Credit checks, fraud prevention and  security_**

We will sometimes need to profile you, for credit, fraud and security purposes.

**Credit checks and ID**

  * We will carry out a credit check when you apply for a contract for any products or services with us.
  * We will also use your personal information for identity verification purposes, for access to your account and for general account management. We sometimes supplement the information we collect about you with information from other sources (for example, the electoral roll and credit reference agencies) to assess the accuracy of the information that we hold.

**Fraud prevention and security**

  * We will process your personal and traffic data in order to protect against and detect fraud, to protect and detect misuse or damage to our networks, to recover debts or trace those who owe us money resulting from the use of our services.

For more details on these, check our [Credit checks](https://www.vodafone.co.uk/about-this-site/our-privacy-policy/credit-checking/) page and our [Fraud](https://www.vodafone.co.uk/about-this-site/our-privacy-policy/Fraud-prevention/) page.

Where applicable, we share information about you with:

  * Companies in the Vodafone Group
  * Partners, suppliers or agents involved in delivering the products and services you’ve ordered or used
  * Companies who are engaged to perform services for, or on behalf of, Vodafone Limited, or Vodafone Group
  * Credit reference, fraud-prevention or business-scoring agencies, or other credit scoring agencies
  * Debt collection agencies or other debt-recovery organisations
  * Law enforcement agencies, government bodies, regulatory organisations, courts or other public authorities if we have to, or are authorised to by law
  * A third party or body where such disclosure is required to satisfy any applicable law, or other legal or regulatory requirement
  * Emergency services (if you make an emergency call), including your approximate location
  * Third parties for joint promotions with that third party. They’ll be responsible for their own compliance with applicable privacy laws
  * Other third parties when you are signing up to their service and it is used by them for authentication and fraud-prevention purposes
  * Third parties that we advertise with, such as Facebook, in order to serve you advertisements online
  * Third parties that we use to serve you marketing, for example, MailChimp

**Fraud management and law enforcement**

  * We will release information if it’s reasonable for the purpose of protecting us against fraud, defending our rights or property, or to protect the interests of our customers.
  * We also may need to release your information to comply with our legal obligation to respond to the authorities’ lawful demands. Your personal data shall only be provided when we in good faith believe we are obliged to do so in accordance with the law and pursuant to an exhaustive evaluation of all legal requirements.

**Mergers and acquisitions**

If we’re reorganised or sold to another organisation, we will provide your information to that organisation.

**Third parties that we work with**

Where you’ve purchased Vodafone products and services using a third party or partner organisation, we often need to exchange information with them as part of managing that relationship and your account – for example, to be able to identify your order and be able to pay them.

If we have a contract with a service provider or contractor to provide us with services or provide a service on our behalf, and they may have access to your personal information, we don’t authorise them to use or disclose your personal information except in connection with providing their services.

We collect and combine information in order to monitor your use of products and services, and that of our other customers, as well as to help us to improve the quality of our products and services.

**Third-party products that you buy through your Vodafone account**

Where you buy a third-party product or service through your Vodafone account (such as [Charge to Bill for mobile](http://www.vodafone.co.uk/explore/music-tv-and-sports/vodafone-charge-to-bill/)), the contract for it is with the party selling that product or service. Vodafone is only charging the amount directly to your bill as part of its arrangements with the seller (or with a third party authorised by the seller). As part of this, you’re agreeing that Vodafone may pass certain personal information to such parties to complete your purchase.

The seller’s terms and conditions and privacy and cookies policies will apply to how it uses your personal information – please read them carefully.

We may need to transfer your information to other Vodafone Group companies or service providers in countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA). The EEA consists of countries in the European Union, Switzerland, Iceland, Liechtenstein and Norway: they are considered to have equivalent laws when it comes to data protection and privacy. This kind of data transfer may happen if our servers (i.e. where we store data) or our suppliers and service providers are based outside the EEA, or if you use our services and products while visiting countries outside this area.

If Vodafone sends your information to a country that is not in the EEA, we will make sure that your information is properly protected. We will always ensure that there is a proper legal agreement that covers the data transfer. In addition, if the country is not considered to have laws that are equivalent to EU data protection standards then we will ask the third party to enter into a legal agreement that reflects those standards.

For information on how long we hold your personal data for, see our [retention schedule](http://www.vodafone.co.uk/cs/groups/public/documents/document/vfcon093713.pdf) [PDF: 57.6KB].

We have specialised security teams who constantly review and improve our measures to protect your personal information from unauthorised access, accidental loss, disclosure or destruction.

Communications over the internet (such as emails) aren’t secure unless they’ve been encrypted. Your communications may go through a number of countries before being delivered, as this is the nature of the internet.

We cannot accept responsibility for any unauthorised access or loss of personal information that is beyond our control.

We’ll never ask for your secure personal or account information by an unsolicited means of communication. You’re responsible for keeping your personal and account information secure and not sharing it with others.

Our website may provide links to third-party websites. We cannot be responsible for the security and content of such third-party websites. So make sure you read that company’s privacy and cookies policies before using or putting your personal information on their site.

The same applies to any third-party websites or content you connect to using our products and services.

You may choose to disclose your information in certain ways such as social plug-ins (including those offered by Google, Facebook, Twitter and Pinterest) or using third-party services that allow you to post reviews or other information publicly, and a third party could use that information.

Social plug-ins and social applications are operated by the social network themselves and are subject to their own terms of use and privacy and cookies policies. You should make sure you’re familiar with these.

Below we set out details on how you can exercise your rights. If you have a question or cannot find the answer, please contact our [Customer Services](https://www.vodafone.co.uk/contact-us/) team or use our [privacy query form](https://www.vodafone.co.uk/gdpr-privacy-query-form/index.htm) and a member of our dedicated team will respond to you.

**Please note:** the privacy query form is not for Subject Access Requests (SARs). To raise a Subject Access Request, please fill in the [Subject Access Request form](https://www.vodafone.co.uk/gdpr-sars-form/)

**Right to access personal data**  
You have the right to make a request for a copy of the personal data that Vodafone holds about you. To make this request as an individual or an authorised third party, visit our [Subject Access Request page](https://www.vodafone.co.uk/gdpr-sars-form/index.htm) which gives details on how to do this. Alternatively, you can contact our [Customer Services](https://www.vodafone.co.uk/contact-us/) team.

**Right to correct personal data**  
You have the right to correct information held about you if it’s not accurate. If the information we hold about you is inaccurate or needs to be updated, you can log in to [My Vodafone](https://www.vodafone.co.uk/myvodafone/faces/home) to update it or you can contact our [Customer Service team](https://www.vodafone.co.uk/contact-us/)

**Right to data portability**  
You have the right to be able to take with you the personal data you provided to us in certain circumstances. Vodafone ensures that you can take your data with you by allowing you to download your monthly bills, at the click of a button. In order to do this, log in to [My Vodafone](https://www.vodafone.co.uk/myvodafone/faces/oracle/webcenter/portalapp/pagehierarchy/Page1.jspx#%40%3F_adf.ctrl-state%3D6r3p4hssa_30) and go to your billing area.

**Right to object to use of personal data**  
You have the right, in certain circumstances, to object to Vodafone processing your personal information. For more information or to exercise this right, please contact our [Customer Services](https://www.vodafone.co.uk/gdpr-privacy-query-form/index.htm) team. If this relates to an automated decision performed on you (this means with no human involvement), please let us know and we will review your request. 

**To opt out of marketing messages:**

If you no longer want to receive marketing messages from Vodafone, you can choose to opt out at any time. If you’ve previously opted in to receive personalised content based on how and where you use our network, you can also opt out at any time.

The easiest way to opt out is by using our marketing preferences page, found under your [My Vodafone](http://www.vodafone.co.uk/privacysettings) account settings.

There are also various other ways to opt out:

  * Contact our customer services team - [see the contact us page](https://www.vodafone.co.uk/contact-us/)
  * Click the link at the end of a marketing email, text or picture message to unsubscribe from that channel
  * Change your communication preferences by texting the relevant code in [this table](http://www.vodafone.co.uk/cs/groups/public/documents/document/vfcon094858.pdf) [PDF: 342KB]
  * Tell the adviser if you receive a marketing call
  * Disable push notification messages, including marketing messages, at any time in our apps by changing the notification settings on your device or by uninstalling the app
  * Contact our [customer data team](https://www.vodafone.co.uk/gdpr-privacy-query-form/index.htm) for guidance

If you’re opted out of marketing, you may still receive service-related messages.

**Please note:  **You may still receive marketing messages for a short period after opting out while we update our records.

You may have received marketing from Vodafone even if you’re not a customer or have never had contact with us. This is a result of third-party marketing lists which Vodafone may acquire from time to time, stating that you have given permission to be contacted by other organisations. If you’ve registered with us to opt out of marketing from Vodafone, you shouldn’t receive such communications. If you still do, we ask that you let us know immediately by contacting our [customer data team](https://www.vodafone.co.uk/gdpr-privacy-query-form/index.htm). This will only stop marketing from us and not stop the third parties from sharing your data unless you contact them directly.

**To manage cookies and understand more about what they are**  
Want to disable a cookie, or understand more about what these are? Check the 'Cookies' section of this Privacy Portal for full details on how to do this.

**To opt out of Vodafone Analytics, or to understand what it means for you**  
While it can’t identify or contact you, it’s your choice whether you’re included. Please see the [Vodafone Analytics](https://www.vodafone.co.uk/about-this-site/our-privacy-policy/vodafone-analytics/index.htm) page.

**How to lodge a complaint**  
If you want to contact us about any of your rights or complain about how we use your information, please use our [privacy query form](https://www.vodafone.co.uk/gdpr-privacy-query-form/index.htm) and a member of our dedicated team will respond to you. Alternatively, you can contact our [Customer Services](https://www.vodafone.co.uk/contact-us/) team – we’ll do our best to help but if you’re still unhappy, you can contact the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO). Their website [www.ico.org.uk](http://www.ico.org.uk/) has details on how to [contact the ICO](https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/).

**Right to restrict use of your data**  
If you feel data we hold on you is inaccurate, or you believe we shouldn’t be processing your data, please contact our [Customer Services](http://www.vodafone.co.uk/contact-us/) team to discuss your rights. In certain circumstances, you have the right to ask us to restrict processing.

**Right to erasure**  
Vodafone strives to only process and retain your data for as long as we need to. In certain circumstances you have the right to request that we erase personal data of yours that we hold. If you feel that we are retaining your data longer than we need, it is worth first checking that your contract with Vodafone has been terminated, which you can do with [Customer Services](http://www.vodafone.co.uk/contact-us/). If your contract with Vodafone has been terminated, we may still have lawful grounds to process your personal data. For more information on retention periods, see the section in this privacy policy called ‘How long do we keep your personal information for?’.

### Privacy and our products and services

 **Our cookies policy**

This section is about what cookies are, how we use them and how you can manage them.

**What are cookies?**

Cookies are small files that are stored on your device when you visit a website. The cookies mean that the website will remember you and how you've used the site every time you come back.

If you want to know more about cookies, head to [aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/ "aboutcookies.org") or [allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) (please note: these links open a new window or browser tab).

**How we use cookies**

We use cookies to do a number of things. For example, remembering your preferences, recording what you've put in your shopping basket, or counting the number of people looking at a website. We also use them to keep track of what you've bought from us, what you've done on the site, and to make online advertising more relevant to you.

Cookies themselves don't hold personal information. They only have a unique alphanumeric identifier that sits on your browser. And in many cases, we won’t be able to link the information we collect by using a cookie back to you. They can, however, enable us to link that information back to you and your personal information, for example, when you log in, or choose to register for a service, white paper or newsletter.

We've put our cookies into the following categories, to make it easier for you to understand why we need them:

  1. Strictly necessary – these are used to help make our website work efficiently.
  2. Performance – these are used to analyse the way our website works and how we can improve it.
  3. Functionality – these help to enhance your experience by doing things like remembering products you've added to your basket.
  4. Targeting/advertising – these are used to share some information with third parties who we advertise with, so we know how you've reached our website. We can also use cookies to identify the parts of the website that you are interested in. We then use this information to show you adverts and pages we think may also be of interest to you, to tailor how we communicate with you, or to tailor the contents of the communications we send to you. If you prefer, you can opt out of these. Tailoring of content means it includes information reflecting the interest you’ve shown in the content of our web pages, or offers or promotions that we think may interest you, and to improve how we respond to your needs.

Sometimes, other Vodafone Group companies will add a cookie to show you adverts and pages which may be of interest to you. Details on these, and how to opt out if you prefer, can be found in the ‘Third-party cookies’ section of this cookies policy.

In addition to the cookies we use on our websites, we also use cookies and similar technologies in some emails and push notifications we send to mobile devices from our apps. These help us to understand whether you have opened the email and how you have interacted with it. If you have enabled images, cookies may be set on your computer or mobile device. Cookies will also be set if you click on any link within the email.

We sometimes use persistent cookies as well as 'session-based' cookies. A 'persistent' cookie will remain for a period of time set for that cookie. A 'session-based' cookie is allocated only for the duration of your visit to our website and automatically expires when you close down your browser.

**Cookies and you**

To make a purchase online or sign up to services like My Vodafone or Vodafone Rewards on Pay as you go, you must have cookies enabled on your internet browser. Some of the more popular browsers are:

If you choose not to enable cookies, you’ll still be able to browse our website, but it will restrict some of the functionality of our website and what you can do.

**First-party cookies**

First-party cookies originate from the same domain as the website you’re currently visiting (in this case, vodafone.co.uk).

See our list of first-party cookies (shown later on in this cookies policy).

**Third-party cookies**

Third-party cookies originate from a domain that’s different to the website being visited. For example, when you visit our website, we may link to another company's website – like our Facebook or Twitter account, or a video from our YouTube page. We don't control how they use their cookies, so we suggest you check their website to see how they're using them and how you can manage them.

Affiliates of the Vodafone Group with a different domain name may also place cookies on our website, to show you adverts or pages of other Vodafone Group companies that may be of interest to you. Details of these affiliates – and how to opt out – are included in our list of third parties (shown later on in this cookies policy) that may put cookies on our website.

**Controlling your cookies**

You can opt in or out of cookies at any time – except strictly necessary cookies (these are used to help make our website work efficiently). Click on the **cookie settings** button to control your cookies, and toggle each cookie to **Active** or **Inactive**. You can select by category or individual cookie.

Go to Cookie Settings

Alternatively, you can enable or disable cookies in your browser. If you wish to restrict or block the cookies set by any website – including a Vodafone website – you can do this through the web browser settings for each web browser you use, on each device you use to access the internet.

Information on controlling and deleting cookies, including on a wide variety of browsers, is also available at [allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

In our cookie policy under the heading 'Cookies and you', we’ve also provided a few links for some of the more popular browsers – but check your particular browser and device for correct and up-to-date information.

Some services – My Vodafone, for example – may not function or may have more limited functionality if your web browser does not accept cookies. However, you can allow cookies from specific websites by making them 'trusted websites' in your web browser.

If you want to opt-out of cookies across different advertising networks The Internet Advertising Bureau website – [Your Online Choices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/) – has more information and guidance.

If you don't wish to accept cookies from one of our emails, you can choose not to download any images or click on any links. You can also set your browser to restrict cookies or to reject them entirely. These settings will apply to all cookies, whether included on websites or in emails. Depending on your email or browser settings, cookies in an email may sometimes be automatically accepted (for example, when you've added an email address to your address book or safe senders list). For more information, refer to your email browser or device instructions.

**What it’s called**

| 

**What it’s used for**

| 

**Type**  
  
---|---|---  
  
utag_main  
x_axis_main

| 

Code management platform that contains logic on what 3rd party code is required by the website. The cookie stores no customer data and doesn't directly change the customer experience.

For more information see [https://tealium.com/cookie-policy/ for more information](https://tealium.com/cookie-policy/%20for%20more%20information)

| 

2  
  
_gat  
_ga  
_gid

| 

Used by Google Analytics to report on the performance of the website, thus helping in campaign optimisation to deliver relevant content and usability improvements.

For more information please see <https://policies.google.com/technologies/cookies>

| 

2  
  
LPVID

| 

Used to enable web chat, allowing you to contact customer services.

For more information please see <http://www.liveperson.com/policies/privacy>

| 

3  
  
ObSSOCookie

| 

Enabling single sign on for logging in from a company network.

| 

1  
  
ASP.NET_SessionId

| 

Used to maintain an anonymised user session by the server.

| 

1  
  
JSESSIONID  
SITESJSESSIONID

| 

If you click back on your browser, our system knows what page you were looking at before.

| 

1  
  
PHPSESSID

| 

This is a general purpose identifier used to maintain user session variables. It is normally a random generated number, how it is used can be specific to the site, i.e. maintaining a logged-in status for a user between pages.

| 

1  
  
BVBRANDSID  
BVBRANDID

| 

Bazaarvoice Analytics service measures and reports on the business impact on 'www.vodafone.co.uk' from the customer generated rating & reviews.

For more information please see <http://www.bazaarvoice.com/privacy-policy/>

| 

4  
  
s_sess  
mbox  
s_fid  
s_pers  
s_vi  
s_cc

| 

We use Adobe’s analytics and on-site personalisation services to measure the use and performance of our website. This may include information such as how you reached one of our web pages, your IP address, and how you interact with our content.

For more information please see <https://www.adobe.com/gr_en/privacy/cookies.html>

| 

2  
  
__utma  
__utmc  
__utmz  
__utmt  
__utmb

| 

Used by Google Analytics to report on the performance of the website, aiding campaign optimisation and usability improvements.

See this link for more information <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245>

This is the link to the Google Opt-Out tool:  
<https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>

| 

2  
  
_gid  
_ga  
_gat

| 

Used by Google Analytics to report on the performance of the website, thus helping in campaign optimisation to deliver relevant content and usability improvements.

See this link for more information <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245>

This is the link to the Google Opt-Out tool:  
<https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>

| 

2  
  
dtPC  
dtLatC  
dtCookie

| 

dtcookie - Session cookie used to identify user sessions. This cookie is valid as long as the browser process is running.  
Dtpc - Page context cookie used to link web requests to user actions.  
dtlatc - Measures server latency for performance monitoring.  
Required to identify proper endpoints for beacon transmission; includes session ID for correlation.

For more information, please see <https://www.dynatrace.com/company/terms-and-conditions/privacy/#cookies-and-other-tracking-technologies>

| 

2  
  
DYN_USER_ID  
DYN_USER_CONFIRM

| 

Temporarily remembers what you're doing on our website, so you don't need to give us the same information twice (for example, when you add a new phone to your basket)  
When you click off our website, the information will be automatically removed.

| 

3  
  
kampyle_userid  
kampyleUserSessionsCount  
kampyleSessionPageCounter  
kampyleUserSession  
kampyleUserPercentile  
kampyleInvitePresented

| 

Customer survey tool.

For more information please see <https://www.medallia.com/privacy-policy/>

| 

3  
  
AMCVS_  
AMCV_

| 

Adobe Marketing Cloud provides the Visitor ID service, using JavaScript to store a unique visitor ID in an AMCV_###@AdobeOrg cookie on the domain of the current website, where ### represents a random string of characters. It is this ID that allows us to serve you more relevant content and experiences.

For more information please see <https://www.adobe.com/uk/privacy/marketing-cloud.html>

| 

4  
  
RT

| 

Soasta provides an availability and performance system monitoring application.

For more information please see <https://www.soasta.com/privacy-policy/>

| 

2  
  
BinkiesVisitorId  
BinkiesSessionId

| 

3D models of devices to provide customers a more lifelike experience.

For more information please see <https://www.binkies3d.com/>

| 

4  
  
vf_returning_visitor

| 

Identifies whether you're a Consumer, Business, Corporate or Public Sector customer – depending on how many times you've clicked on each section of our website  
It means that when you arrive at our website, our system will remember which area should be shown to you automatically

| 

3  
  
x-vodafone-solo

| 

The skip login feature has been added to My Vodafone to improve the experience. If you click on ‘Skip login to this page next time’, your phone, tablet or laptop will bypass the login page next time you come to the site. This cookie will be set for 30 days and only allow you to access some of the My Vodafone pages. You’ll still need to fully login to perform other tasks. We don’t recommend you use this feature on public or shared devices, as the cookie will remain on the device after use.

| 

3   
  
bp_sid  
bp_test  
bp_tid  
referral_tracking | 

Used to track journeys made on our website following an individual providing another individual with a ‘refer a friend’ link to Vodafone services. 

For more information please see [www.buyapowa.com/platform-privacy-policy](https://www.buyapowa.com/platform-privacy-policy)

| 3  
  
We are currently reviewing our lists and will update them from time to time.

**Company**

| 

**What it's called**

| 

**Type**

| 

**More Information**  
  
---|---|---|---  
  
Davinic11 (Ad2One)

| 

IDE  
_uetsid

| 

4

| 

For more information please see <https://pages.ebay.co.uk/help/account/cookies-web-beacons.html>

For more information about opting out, please see <https://pages.ebay.co.uk/help/account/adchoice.html>  
  
Adform

| 

 uid  
 cid  
CM14  
DigiTrust.v1.identity  
TPC  
C

| 

4

| 

For more information please see <https://site.adform.com/privacy-policy-opt-out/>

For more information about opting out, please see <https://site.adform.com/privacy-policy-opt-out/>  
  
Amazon

| 

ad-id  
ad-privacy

| 

4

| 

For more information please see <https://services.amazon.co.uk/standards/cookies.html>__  
  
Oath

| 

B  
ACID  
ASCID  
C2

| 

4

| 

For more information please see <https://policies.oath.com/us/en/oath/privacy/topics/cookies/index.html>  
  
AppNexus

| 

anj  
sess  
uuid2

| 

4

| 

For more information please see <https://www.appnexus.com/en/company/cookie-policy>

For more information about opting out, please see <https://www.appnexus.com/en/company/platform-privacy-policy#choices>  
  
Affiliate Window

| 

AWSESS  
aw1257  
aw1856  
aw2220  
aw2306  
aw2363

| 

_4_

| 

For more information please see <https://www.awin.com/gb/legal/privacy-policy>  
  
Bing

| 

MUID  
MUIDB  
ANON  
NAP  
SRCHD  
SRCHUID  
SRCHUSR  
_EDGE_V  
B

| 

4

| 

For more information please see <https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-gb/privacystatement>  
  
Captify

| 

anj  
sess  
uuid2

| 

4

| 

For more information please see <http://www.captify.co.uk/privacy-policy/>  
  
MediaIQ

| 

anj  
sess  
uuid2  
IDE  
_uetsid

| 

_4_

| 

For more information please see <https://mediaiqdigital.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/privacy-policy-new.pdf>  
  
Facebook

| 

fr  
datr  
lu

| 

4

| 

For more information please see <https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/>  
  
Google

| 

GAPS  
LSID  
APISID  
SSID  
NID  
SID  
SAPISID  
HSID  
VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE  
PREF  
YSC  
IDE  
 _uetsid  
CONSENT  
1_JAR  
UULE  
OTZ  
SIDCC  
AID

| 

_2_

| 

See this link for more information <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245>

This is the link to the Google Opt-Out tool:  
<https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>  
  
Gumtree

| 

IDE  
_uetsid

| 

4

| 

For more information please see <https://www.gumtree.com/cookies>

For more information about opting out, please see <https://www.ebay.com/help/account/adchoice/adchoice?id=4648>  
  
LinkedIn

| 

BizoID  
UserMatchHistory  
lang  
lidc  
bcookie  
__utma  
__utmv  
__qca  
bscookie

| 

4

| 

For more information please see <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy>

For more information about opting out, please see <https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls/retargeting-opt-out?trk>=  
  
Plista

| 

Pookie  
rt11

| 

4

| 

For more information please see <https://www.plista.com/about/privacy/>

For more information about opting out, please see <https://www.plista.com/about/opt-out/>  
  
Videology (Tidal TV)

| 

tidal_ttid  
adidt  
sync-his  
tpdpc  
tpfreqcap  
ttvrc

| 

4

| 

 For more information on how Videology use your Personal Data, please see: <https://videologygroup.com/en/privacy-policy>

For more information about opting out of Interest-Based Ads you can, please see <https://videologygroup.com/en/learn-about-interest-based-ads-opt-out>  
  
Twitter

| 

auth_token  
twll  
secure_session  
guest_id  
__utma  
personalization_id  
remember_checked  
 remember_checked_on  
lang

| 

4

| 

For more information please see <https://help.twitter.com/en/rules-and-policies/twitter-cookies>  
  
Xaxis

| 

id  
mdata

| 

4

| 

For more information please see <https://www.xaxis.com/privacy-policy/>

For more information about opting out <https://www.xaxis.com/opt-out/>  
  
App Dynamics

| 

_actmu  
_actvc  
_ga  
_mkto_trk  
ajs_anonymous_id  
ajs_group_id  
ajs_user_id  
ei_client_id  
optimizelyEndUserId  
ser_app

| 

_2_

| 

For more information please see <https://www.appdynamics.com/cookie-policy/>  
  
Adobe Audience Manager

| 

DST  
_dp  
demdex  
dextp  
dpm

| 

_4_

| 

For more information please see <https://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html#5>

For more information about opting out: <https://www.adobe.com/uk/privacy/opt-out.html>  
  
Doubleclick

| 

_uetsid  
 id  
DSID  
IDE

| 

_4_

| 

You can control the ads that you see on Google and find out more about how the ads are selected for you by visiting [www.google.com/settings/ads](http://www.google.com/settings/ads)

Alternatively, you can also manage and opt-out of Google DoubleClick and other third party cookies by visiting  
  
Freespee

| 

__fs_uid  
AWSELB

| 

_4_

| 

For more information please see <https://www.freespee.com/about/privacy-policy/>  
  
LivePerson

| 

LivePersonID  
LPVisitorID  
LPSessionID

| 

_3_

| 

For more information please see <https://www.liveperson.com/policies/privacy>  
  
Mookie (media innovation group)

| 

id  
mdata  
OAX

| 

_4_

| 

For more information or to find out how to opt out, please see [http://www.themig.com/en-us/privacy.html#](http://www.themig.com/en-us/privacy.html)  
  
Nanorep

| 

u  
271AABB  
2404866  
265975C  
240485E  
26597CD  
2404863  
2659761  
26597D2  
271AABB  
271AAC0

| 

_3_

| 

For more information please see <https://www.logmeininc.com/legal/privacy>

For more information about opting out <http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/>  
  
Medallia

| 

us_lang

| 

_3_

| 

For more information please see <https://www.medallia.com/privacy-policy/>

For more information about opting out <http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/>  
  
Adobe Target

| 

mbox.

| 

_4_

| 

For more information, please see <https://www.adobe.com/gr_en/privacy/cookies.html>

For more information about opting out, please see <https://www.adobe.com/gr_en/privacy/opt-out.html>  
  
Veinteractive

| 

__ssid  
ouuid  
ouuid_last_update

| 

_4_

| 

For more information, please see <https://www.ve.com/cookies-policy>

For more information about opting out, please see <https://www.ve.com/privacy-policy#opting-out>  
  
Quantcast

| 

d  
mc

| 

_4_

| 

For more information, please see <https://www.quantcast.com/privacy/>

For more information about opting out, please see <https://www.quantcast.com/opt-out/>  
  
Bazaar Voice

| 

BVID

| 

_4_

| 

For more information, please see <https://www.bazaarvoice.com/legal/privacy-policy/>

For more information about opting out, please see <https://www.bazaarvoice.com/legal/privacy-policy/#opting-out>  
  
Bidswitch (IPONWEB)

| 

c  
tuuid_lu  
tuuid

| 

_4_

| 

For more information, please see <http://www.bidswitch.com/privacy-policy/>  
  
ELOQUA

| 

ELOQUA  
 ELQSTATUS

| 

_4_

| 

For more information, please see <https://www.oracle.com/legal/privacy/privacy-policy.html#cookie-preferences>

For more information about opting out, please see <https://www.oracle.com/marketingcloud/about/index.html>  
  
Adroll

| 

__adroll

| 

_4_

| 

For more information, please see <https://www.adrollgroup.com/privacy>

For more information about opting out, please see <https://app.adroll.com/optout/safari>  
  
Rockabox

| 

tuuid, pcc, pvc

| 

_4_

| 

For more information, please see <http://scoota.com/privacy-policy/>  
  
Adobe Media Optimizer

| 

everest_session_v2  
everest_g_v2  
ev_sync_dd

| 

4

| 

For more information, please see <https://marketing.adobe.com/resources/help/en_US/whitepapers/cookies/cookies_media_optimizer.html>  
  
Google Analytics

| 

__utma  
__utmc  
__utmz  
__utmt  
__utmb  
G_ENABLED_IDPS  
disqus_unique  
__jid

| 

2

| 

For more information, please see <https://policies.google.com/technologies/managing>  
  
Indeed

| 

CTK  
BIGipServerjob  
INDEED_CSRF_TOKEN  
JSESSIONID

|  | 

For more information please see <https://www.indeed.com/legal#cookies>  

* * *

You can ask us about how we use your details for fraud prevention when you take out your Vodafone agreement.

We may release details of your agreement with us to credit-reference agencies, debt-collection agencies and fraud-prevention agencies. This could include changes of address, payments made, account balances, missed payments, disputes and queries.

We, and other organisations, may also access and use this information to prevent fraud and money laundering for example, when checking details on applications for credit or other credit-related facilities, managing credit and credit-related accounts or facilities, recovering debt, checking details on proposals and claims for all types of insurance.

We, and other organisations, may also access and use any information recorded by fraud-prevention agencies from other countries.

Please [contact us](http://www.vodafone.co.uk/contact-us/) if you want to receive details of the relevant fraud prevention agencies.

1.  Before we provide services, goods or finances to you (as applicable), we undertake checks for the purposes of preventing fraud and money laundering, and to verify your identity. These checks require us to process personal data about you.

2.  The personal data you’ve provided, we’ve collected from you, or we’ve received from third parties will be used to prevent fraud and money laundering, and to verify your identity.

3.  Details of the personal information that will be processed include, for example: name, address, date of birth, contact details, financial information, employment details, device identifiers including IP address and vehicle details.

4.  We and fraud prevention agencies may also enable law enforcement agencies to access and use your personal data to detect, investigate and prevent crime.

5.  We process your personal data on the basis that we have a legitimate interest in preventing fraud and money laundering, and to verify identity, in order to protect our business and to comply with laws that apply to us. Such processing is also a contractual requirement of the services or financing you have requested.

6.  Fraud prevention agencies can hold your personal data for different periods of time, and if you are considered to pose a fraud or money laundering risk, your data can be held for up to six years.

7.  As part of the processing of your personal data, decisions may be made by automated means. This means we may automatically decide that you pose a fraud or money laundering risk if our processing reveals your behaviour to be consistent with money laundering or known fraudulent conduct, or is inconsistent with your previous submissions, or you appear to have deliberately hidden your true identity. You have rights in relation to automated decision making: if you want to know more please [submit your query](https://www.vodafone.co.uk/gdpr-privacy-query-form) and a member of our dedicated team will respond to you, or if you would like to contact us by post, send it marked **The Privacy Team** to Vodafone House, The Connection, Newbury, Berkshire, RG14 2FN.

8\.  If we, or a fraud prevention agency, determine that you pose a fraud or money laundering risk, we may refuse to provide the services you have requested, or to employ you, or we may stop providing existing services to you.  

9\.  A record of any fraud or money laundering risk will be retained by the fraud prevention agencies, and may result in others refusing to provide services, financing or employment to you.

10.  Whenever fraud prevention agencies transfer your personal data outside of the European Economic Area, they impose contractual obligations on the recipients of that data to protect your personal data to the standard required in the European Economic Area. They may also require the recipient to subscribe to ‘international frameworks’ intended to enable secure data sharing.

11.  Your personal data is protected by legal rights. If you want to know more or to exercise these, see the Your Rights section of the main [Privacy Policy](https://www.vodafone.co.uk/privacy#/privacy-policy)

12.  We want to ensure you have access to all the information you need to understand how we manage fraud prevention and your personal data. If you have any questions, please [submit your query](https://www.vodafone.co.uk/gdpr-privacy-query-form) and a member of our dedicated team will respond to you, or if you would like to contact us by post, send it marked **The Privacy Team** to Vodafone House, The Connection, Newbury, Berkshire, RG14 2FN.
